# Travis Lawrence

- > Ruby on Rails Developer
- > SQL Database
- > JavaScript
- > Backbone JS
- > HTML5 & CSS3
- > Sinatra (Ruby)
- > TDD & Agile Practices

805.835.3471 travis.lawrence12@gmail.com www.github.com/TravisL12 travisL12.herokuapp.com www.linkedin.com/in/travislawrence12

110 Broderick Street #9 San Francisco, CA 94117

### **OBJECTIVE**

Achieve a position as a full stack web developer with an organization that embraces agile development and best practices.

I have a strong interest in identifying trends based on behavior even in my own routine. For the past several years I've been tracking and charting my mileage driven, number of days biked to work, and many other metrics while always looking for new ways to parse my personal data.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Web Developer

2013 - Present Dev Bootcamp

- > Throughout this nine week program I learned Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript and jQuery and exercised pair programming, SQL database management, and built several Ruby on Rails apps.
- > Built and presented, to prospective employers and fellow students, our final project: Bounty Cove (bountycove.herokuapp.com). Our team of four produced this site over our final week of Dev Bootcamp. I was responsible for back-end development of the users and tasks models (including RSpec testing) and various front-end AJAX interactions.
- > Worked, contractually, on Worldly.com, MeoGraph.com and Kinstantly.com. Submitted pull requests that were pushed to production.

### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- > Social Platform API knowledge (Facebook, Twitter, etc.)
- > Emphasis on writing courteous and readable Code
- > Adept with Photoshop & Illustrator
- > Exceptional at MS Excel
- > Comfortable with Unix and Linux Environments

#### **EDUCATION**

### M.Sc. Audio Acoustics

2005 - 2006 University of Salford, Manchester, UK

> Studied various acoustics topics including room acoustics, transducers, digital signal processing, and psychoacoustics.

# **B.S.** Theoretical Physics

1999 - 2004 University of California at Riverside

> Studied a wide range of physics, and mathematics including electromagnetism, analog and digital electronics, holography, and astrophysics.

# Travis Lawrence

- > Ruby on Rails Developer
- > SQL Database
- > JavaScript
- > HTML5 & CSS3
- > Sinatra (Ruby)
- > TDD & Agile Practices

805.835.3471

travis.lawrence12@gmail.com www.github.com/TravisL12 travisL12.herokuapp.com www.linkedin.com/in/travislawrence12

110 Broderick Street #9 San Francisco, CA 94117

### **PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT**

### **Acoustical Consultant**

2010 - 2013 Charles Salter Associates, San Francisco, CA

- > Worked directly with principal consultants for a multitude of acoustical projects including theatres, museums, educational, commercial, and residential projects.
- > Successfully completed numerous projects from schematic design to construction drawings. Performed final site walks with contractor/architects.
- > Collaborated with the Center for the Built Environment at UC Berkeley to develop a new acoustical standard for low-cost, effective speech privacy testing and measurement.

2007 - 2010 Mei Wu Acoustics, Redwood City, CA

- Performed acoustical tests in accordance with international standards for industrial noise control, government complexes, and residential high rises.
  Developed 3D models to predict acoustical conditions, design sound systems, and provide architectural recommendations.
- > Designed and built the long-term (3 years) noise monitoring system for the Caldecott Tunnel 4<sup>th</sup> Bore project.

### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

### Music

- > A lifelong passion for music initially led me to the acoustics field.
- > Self taught to play guitar over 10 years ago and still avidly playing nearly everyday.

# Computers & Technology

- > Avid follower of the latest technology news with a particular focus on computers and smartphones.
- > Enjoy building, modifying, and troubleshooting computer hardware.
- > Recreational experience with graphics design and web design.
- > Special interests include astronomy, physics, and the advancement of environmentally conscious technology.

# **Recreation & Sports**

- > Three time marathon finisher (San Francisco 2x & San Diego).
- > Lifelong soccer enthusiast, still playing in city leagues since moving to San Francisco over 5 years ago.